Guide to the Arch Brown papers, circa 1955-2012.
Brown, Arch papers
- Manuscripts
  - Play Scripts
    - Peace by Piece, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Script from a performance at the Thorny Theater
    - "Dr. Farce", undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
      No author credit given. Corrections are in Arch Brown's hand.
    - Misc. scripts, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
      No author credit given. Audion scripts mostly are drawn from Arch Brown's plays.
      Includes excerpt from Caryl Churchill's "Cloud 9" which was produced by the Thorny Theater.
    - Untitled script, untitled (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Incomplete, possibly an early playwriting attempt.
      No author credit given but corrections are in Arch Brown's hand.
    - "Give us the Night" by Jack Weiser; "To Find Something Blue", undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Mr. Charles, Currently of Palm Beach" by Paul Rudnick, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Other Manuscript and Printed Material
    - 3 Sex Comics, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
      "Henry in 'The Only Way'"; Didddle Daley Presents The Katzenjammers in 'Shipwrecked'"; "The Frigidaire Salesman"; "Iona Douche Bag presents Tille in 'Foul Ball'"; "Dagwood in 'The Facts of Life'"; "Boots"
    - "Harry, Eric and Death", undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Novel by "Al Krown" which seems to be a pseudonym for Arnold Krueger and Bruce Brown.
    - Early Novel, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Corrections in Arch Brown's hand.
    - Letters of rejection related to the novel "Pornographer"., March 1978-January 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Pornographer (table of contents - page 99, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Pornographer (page 100-202), 1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "The Country", c. early 1970s (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Script for a film by Arch Brown
    - notebooks, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      2 notebooks only a few pages used. One is marked Joel Winkelas and the other Barry Northwoods
- Theater and the Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation
  - Production Materials
    - Cast photos and poster for the Thorny Theater production of "Kitchen Duty...After Eleven", early 1980s - 2000s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Model and actor releases, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Model and actor releases and casting sheets, 1987, 1992, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Agents and publishers rejections, 1990-1998 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Freeze!" Adobe Oven theater, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Freeze!" Adobe Oven theater, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Freeze!" Adobe Oven theater, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      Prints
    - Freeze! New York, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Freeze! Miranda, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - New Phoenix Theater Prize, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Ledger, marked Jack Ellison, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Sir Real - receipts, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Research, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Thorny Theater and the Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation
    - Thorny Theater construction, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Ticket Web user agreement, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Thorny Theater, c. 2006-2010 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      Various materials including event postcards, promotional materials, cast photos.
    - Thorny Theater, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Box Office Reports/Expenses, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Profit and Loss Annual, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Godparents, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      List of donors to the theater.
    - Godparents, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Promotional Materials, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Box Office Reports/Expenses, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Subscribers, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Thorny Theater, c. 2007-2010 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      Mainly cast photos and other promotional material.
    - Profit and Loss Annual, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Quicken report, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Refunds/Credits, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Treasurer's report, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      For the Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation
    - Arch's contributions, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Bank of America - Foundation, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Bank of America - Theater, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Service (1099 employees), 2008 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Advertising, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Godparents, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Business License, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - "108 Waverly" - ticket sales and expenses, February-March 2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "The Bombay Trunk" - ticket sales and expenses, April-May 2008 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Samson" - ticket sales and expenses, June-July 2008 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Sex Symbols" - ticket sales and expenses, September-October 2008 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "The Judy Show" - ticket sales and expenses, December 2008 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Subscribers, 2008-2009 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Promotional materials and clippings, 2008-2009 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Profit and Loss Annual, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Quicken report, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Banks of America - Theater, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Bank of America - Foundation, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Labor detail, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Advertising, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Phone orders (sample), 2009 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "May 27th and Dudes" - Head shots, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Porn Yesterday" - ticket sales and expenses, December 2008-February 2009 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Cloud 9" - ticket sales and expenses, February-March 2009 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Dangerous" - ticket sales and expenses, March-April 2009 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - "Blowing Whistles" - ticket sales and expenses, May 2009 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "Forever After" - ticket sales and expenses, June 2009 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - "Chiaroscuro" - ticket sales and expenses, July-August 2009 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - "Candy and Dorothy" - ticket sales and expenses, October-November 2009 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - "May 27th and Dudes", November-December 2009 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Profit and Loss Annual, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Quicken report, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Bank of America - Theater, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Bank of America - Foundation, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Labor deatil, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Advertising, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "Two Married Men" - ticket sales and expenses, January 2010 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Mansky's Burlyesque" - ticket sales and expenses, February 2010 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "A Perfect Relationship" - ticket sales and expenses, March-April 2010 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "Mansky's Burlyesque" - ticket sales and expenses, April-May 2010 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - "P.S. Your Cat is Dead" - ticket sales and expenses, May-June 2010 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - "Love! Valor! Compassion!" - ticket sales and expenses, July 2010 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Press Clippings, December 2006 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Press Clippings, April 2007 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Press Clippings, December 2007 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Press Clippings, January and March 2008 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Press Clippings, January-August 2009 (Box 9, Folder 41-48)
    - Press Clippings, October-December 2009 (Box 9, Folder 49-51)
      missing September
    - Press Clippings, January-June 2010 (Box 9, Folder 52-57)
    - The Bottom Line magazine, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 58)
      3 issues
    - The Bottom Line magazine, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Magazines, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Desert Theater League Award for Best Drama, 2007; MU-2086 (Box 1)
    - Tackee David Award for Best New Retail Business, 2007; MU-2087 (Box 1)
    - 2nd Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation Board Meeting, 1995-09-11; TR-15676 (Box 4)
    - 3rd Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation Board Meeting, 1996-08-29; TR-15677 (Box 4)
    - 4th Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation Board Meeting, 1997-09-12; TR-15678-15679 (Box 4)
  - Posters, Flyers and Other Promotional Materials
    - "News Boy" (surplus), 1979-1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Materials related to productions of "News Boy" in New York (1980), San Francisco (1981), and Dallas (1985). This includes reviews, programs, ads, cast photos and actor headshots.
      Also includes materials related to New York production of Doric Wilson's a "Perfect Relationship" which ran in repertory with "News Bot" in 1980.
    - "News Boy" - Arizona, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Top Story", 1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Fliers and news clippings
    - "Freeze!" - Buffalo, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Photos, fliers and clippings
    - Freeze!" - Miranda, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      posters and clippings
    - Pantheon - Hollywood, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Includes zip disk and photographs
    - Pantheon - Hollywood, 2001; ZD-6 (Box 10)
    - Pantheon - Hollywood, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Magazines
    - Sir Real!, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Flyers and clippings
    - Thorny Theater Productions, 2006-2008 and undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Flyers, cast photographs, posters and other oversized materials
    - Posters, c. 2006-2010 and undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Mainly for Thorny Theater productions.
      Some early productions appear as well.
    - News Boy, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - News clippings, 2009-2010 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Television Reviews and articles written by Arch Brown, 1981-1983, undated (Box 13)
      Scrapbook. TV reviews written by Arch Brown for the New York Native, The Villager, and other publications.
    - Theater and play clippings, 1980-1985, undated (Box 13)
      Scrapbook. Includes reviews, fan letters, programs, cast photos, for New York City productions of "Sex Symbols" (1982), "Brute Force" (1984), and the San Francisco production of "News Boy" (1981).
    - Gay City Magazine, October 9, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Contains an obituary for Arch Brown.
- Media
  All DVDs and CDs have been digitized and must be accessed via the RMC server.
  - Sir Real!, 2003; DVD-1064 (Box 4)
  - Sir Real!, undated; DVD-1065
  - Chiaroscuro, undated; DVD-1066
  - Shapeshifter, undated; DVD-1067
  - Two Married Men, undated; DVD-1068
  - Thorny Theater: Sex Symbols, undated; DVD-1069
  - Arch: Circus Music 1st Demo, 2003; CD-2049
  - Stefan Girardet - 13 "Library" Tracks, undated; CD-2050
  - Anna Lives, undated; CD-2051
  - Anna Lives sound effects, undated; CD-2052
  - Ancient - Clip Art, undated; CD-2052a
  - 4 Percussion Stings for "Sir Real", undated; CD-2053
  - Stefan Girardet - Track 4 (Backup Copy), CD-2054
  - Stefan Girardet - Film Show reel, undated; CD-2055
  - Mensky's Burlyesque, undated; CD-2056
  - Fleet's Music for "Samson", 2008; CD-2057
  - New Master Instrumentals "Samson", c. 2008; CD-2058
  - New Master Instrumentals "Samson", 2008; CD-2059
  - Samson, c. 2008; CD-2060
  - Act 2 Music for "Samson", 2008; CD-2061-2062
  - New Master, undated; CD-2063
  - Master CD, undated; CD-2064
  - Til There Was You, CD-2065
  - Thorny Theater: Finals by Grag Day, 2010; CD-2066
  - Thorny Theater by Grag Day - Raw Images, undated; CD-2067
  - Arch - Line Dance, undated; CD-2068
  - Love! Valor! Compassion! - Acts 1 and 2, 2010; CD-2069-2070
  - For Arch - "Burlyesque", undated; CD-2071
  - APR w/Summer Ad SQ1-2, undated; CD-2072
  - "Dangerous" - SQ1-10, undated; CD-2073
  - "Dangerous" - SQ1-10, undated; CD-2074
  - "The Goddess Tour", CD-2075-2077
  - Cloud 9, CD-2078-2081
  - Act 2 Samson (Instrumental Music), May-June 2008
    Empty case. Cover has list of songs.
  - Arch Brown's "Top Story" (2 copies), 1993; V-7039-7040 (Box 4)
  - "Sir Real" Version 2, 2004; V-7035 (Box 4)
  - "The Goddess Tour", 2007; V-7036 (Box 4)
  - Circe's Circus - B Roll Footage, undated; V-7033-7034 (Box 4)
    Reel 4 and 5
  - Arch Brown Tape #1-5, undated; V-7030-7032 (Box 4)
    Reel 1-3
  - Love Thy Neighbor, undated; V-7037 (Box 4)
  - Trips, undated; V-7038 (Box 4)
  - Music for Arch Brown's "The Night Before" - Reel 1 and 2, 1973; TR-10101-10102 (Box 4)
  - Happy Birthday from Wayne Dean, 1984; TR-10103 (Box 4)
  - News Boy - Romantic Overture, undated; TR-10104 (Box 4)
  - "Bound" Reel II, undated; TR-10105 (Box 4)
  - Archer Sex Tape, undated; TR-10106 (Box 4)
  - "Thode" Side II - Best, undated; TR-10107 (Box 4)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Broadhurst, Kent. The Eye of the Beholder, 1982 (cover reads "Acting for Actors The Stanislavosky Method")
Meltzer, Daniel. Movie of the Month: A One-Act Play, 1982
Brown, Arch. News Boy, 1979
Brown, Arch. News Boy, 2008, 2nd. Edition
Bumbalo, Victor. Questa, 2006 (signed and inscribed by author)
Churchill, Caryl. Cloud Nine, 1979 (annotated)
Churchill, Caryl. Cloud Nine, 2006 (annotated)
Murray, Joel. High Fortune: A Ten-Minute Comedy Duet, 2002
Crowley, Mart. For Reasons that Remain Unclear, 1995, 2003
Dyer, Charles. Staircase, 1966
Giles, D.B. Men's Singles, 1982 (cover reads "Acting for Actors The Stanislavosky Method"
Chesley, Robert. Plays by Robert Hesley, 2005 (Stray Dog Story, Jerker, and Dog Plays)
Rudnick, Paul. Mr. Charles, Currently of Palm Beach, 2004
Shanley, John Patrick. Welcome to the Moon and Other Plays, 1985
Smith, Tom. Dangerous, 2003
Thomas, Buddy. The Crumple Zone, 2001
Tremblay, Michel. Hosanna, 1991
Tremblay, Michel. Remember Me, 1981
Vanda. Vile Affections, c.2006 (autographed, dated)
Wilson, Doric. A Perfect Relationship and The West Street Gang, 1979 (signed and inscribed by author)
Wilson, Doric. Street Theater, 1982 (signed and inscribed by author)
Wilson, Doric. And He Made a Her, 2006 (includes a CD recording of the 1961 original production)
Desert Business Association. Greater Palm Springs Area Directory, 2006
The Dramatists Guild, Inc. The Dramatists Guild Quarterly, 1993-1994
The Dramatists Guild, Inc. The Dramatists Guild Resource Directory, 2004
The Dramatists Guild, Inc. The Dramatists Guild Resource Directory, 2008
Hanson, Joseph. Ghosts: Poems 1976-1996, 1996 (signed and inscribed by author)
Hanson, Joseph. Pretty Boy Dead, 1977, 1984 (signed and inscribed by author)
Hanson, Joseph. Brandstetter and Others, 1986(inside cover: "From the Library of Sea Park, St. Croix)
Hanson, Joseph. Fadeout, 1980 (signed and inscribed by author)
Hanson, Joseph. Skinflick, 1980 (signed and inscribed by author)
Hanson, Joseph. Nightwork, 1984 (note inside reads, "Compliments of the Author")
Hanson, Joseph. There was a Man Everybody was Afraid Of, 1981 (inside cover: "From the Library of Sea Park, St. Croix))
Hanson, Joseph. The Little Dog Laughed, 1987 (inside cover: "From the Library of Sea Park, St. Croix))
Helbing, Terry. Gay Theater Alliance: Directory of Gay Plays, 1980
Luongo, Michael T. Gay Travels in the Muslim World, 2007
Suresha, Ron Jackson and Chvany, Pete Bi Men: Coming Out Every which Way, 2005
Tilchen, Maida. Land Beyond Maps, 2009 (signed and inscribed by author)
Trevens, Francine L. Echoes of Eternity, 2007 (signed and inscribed by author)
Union Theological Seminary. Union Seminary Quarterly Review, 1983 (Artwork by Arch Brown)
Suresha, Ron Jackson and Chvany, Pete Bi Men: Coming Out Every which Way, in the Journal of Bisexuality, Vol. 5, Num. 2/3 2005